Registerof the Germany. Reichsministerium für Volksaufklärung und Propaganda Miscellaneous Records, 1939-1943
Hoover Institution Archives
Germany. Reichsministerium für Volksaufklärung und Propaganda Miscellaneous Records,
1939-1943
XX185
Germany. Reichsministerium für Volksaufklärung und Propaganda
4 manuscript boxes (1.6 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Political newsletters, radio broadcast transcripts, and letters of radio listeners. Includes an abstract of a speech given before the Berlin Association of Foreign Correspondents on October 14, 1941, and a protocol of the Ministry for Eastern European Affairs regarding its session for October 9, 1943.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Access Points
Fritzsche, Hans, 1900-1953.; Nationalsozialistische deutsche Arbeiter-Partei.; National socialism.; Propaganda, German.; World War, 1939-1945.; World War, 1939-1945--Germany.; World War, 1939-1945--Propaganda.; Germany.
Container List
- Politische Zeitungs- und Rundfunkschau, vorgetragen von Hans Fritzsche (transcripts), 1940 (Box 1)
  - January 2 (Folder 1: 1)
  - January 4 (Folder 1: 2)
  - January 6 (Folder 1: 3)
  - January 9 (Folder 1: 4)
  - January 11 (Folder 1: 5)
  - January 13 (Folder 1: 6)
  - January 16 (Folder 1: 7)
  - January 18 (Folder 1: 8)
  - January 20 (Folder 1: 9)
  - January 23 (Folder 1: 10)
  - January 25 (Folder 1: 11)
  - January 27 (Folder 1: 12)
  - February 1 (Folder 1: 13)
  - February 3 (Folder 1: 14)
  - February 6 (Folder 1: 15)
  - February 8 (Folder 1: 16)
  - February 10 (Folder 1: 17)
  - February 13 (Folder 1: 18)
  - February 15 (Folder 1: 19)
  - February 17 (Folder 1: 20)
  - February 20 (Folder 1: 21)
  - February 22 (Folder 1: 22)
  - February 27 (Folder 1: 23)
  - February 29 (Folder 1: 24)
  - March 2 (Folder 1: 25)
  - March 5 (Folder 1: 26)
  - March 9 (Folder 1: 27)
  - March 12 (Folder 1: 28)
  - March 14 (Folder 1: 29)
  - March 16 (Folder 1: 30)
  - March 19 (Folder 1: 31)
  - March 21 (Folder 1: 32)
  - March 23 (Folder 1: 33)
  - March 26 (Folder 1: 34)
  - March 28 (Folder 1: 35)
  - March 30 (Folder 1: 36)
  - April 2 (Folder 1: 37)
  - April 4 (Folder 1: 38)
  - April 9 (Folder 1: 39)
  - April 11 (Folder 1: 40)
  - April 13 (Folder 1: 41)
  - April 16 (Folder 1: 42)
  - April 18 (Folder 1: 43)
  - April 20 (Folder 1: 44)
- Correspondence (Box 2-3)
  - Listeners mail to Hans Fritzsche, alphabetic by writer (Box 2-3)
    - A (Folder 2: 1)
    - B (Folder 2: 2)
    - C (Folder 2: 3)
    - D (Folder 2: 4)
    - E (Folder 2: 5)
    - F (Folder 2: 6)
    - G (Folder 2: 7)
    - H (Folder 2: 8)
    - I-J (Folder 2: 9)
    - K (Folder 2: 10)
    - M (Folder 2: 11)
    - N (Folder 2: 12)
    - O (Folder 2: 13)
    - P-Q (Folder 3: 1)
    - R (Folder 3: 2)
    - S (Folder 3: 3)
    - T (Folder 3: 4)
    - U (Folder 3: 5)
    - V (Folder 3: 6)
    - W (Folder 3: 7)
    - X-Z (Folder 3: 8)
  - Listeners mail to Hans Fritzsche, anonymous (Box 3)
    - 1940, October-December (Folder 3: 9)
    - 1941 (Box 3)
    - January-March (Folder 3: 10)
    - April-May (Folder 3: 11)
    - June-July (Folder 3: 12)
    - August (Folder 3: 13)
    - September-October (Folder 3: 14)
    - November-December (Folder 3: 15)
    - 1942, January-March (Folder 3: 16)
  - Hans Fritzsche, official correspondence (Box 4)
    - Propaganda Ministry (Albrecht), 1941, July-September (Folder 4: 1)
    - Geheime Staatspolizei (Gestapo, Berlin Headquarters), 1940-1942 (Folder 4: 2)
- Hans Fritzsche, other documentation (Box 4)
  - Abschrift (Notes), Berlin, 14 October 1941, of speech given by Fritzsche at foreign correspondents meeting (Folder 4: 3)
- Other documents (Box 4)
  - Press briefings (Presse Rundschreiben), 1939 (Box 4)
    - June 1-15 (Folder 4: 4)
    - June 17-30 (Folder 4: 5)
    - July 1-15 (Folder 4: 6)
    - July 17-31 (Folder 4: 7)
    - August 1-15 (Folder 4: 8)
    - August 16-30 (Folder 4: 9)
    - November 1-15 (Folder 4: 10)
    - November 17-30 (Folder 4: 11)
    - December 1-15 (Folder 4: 12)
    - December 16-30 (Folder 4: 13)
  - Material related to administration of propaganda in occupied territories in the East (Box 4)
    - "Protokoll des Ostministeriums über die Sitzung vom 16.9.1943" (Folder 4: 14)
    - Memorandum, "Aufbau des Propaganda-Apparates im Ostraum auf Grund der Führer-Entscheidung,", 1943 August 21 (Folder 4: 15)